<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: Copyright (c) 2022 GARDENA GmbH
SPDX-License-Identifier: LicenseRef-GARDENA
-->
<LWM2M xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.openmobilealliance.org/tech/profiles/LWM2M-v1_1.xsd">
    <Object ObjectType="MODefinition">
		<Name>Missions</Name>
		<Description1><![CDATA[]]></Description1>
		<ObjectID>31404</ObjectID>
		<ObjectURN>urn:oma:lwm2m:x:31404:0.1</ObjectURN>
		<LWM2MVersion>1.1</LWM2MVersion>
		<ObjectVersion>0.1</ObjectVersion>
		<MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
		<Mandatory>Optional</Mandatory>
		<Resources>
			<Item ID="1">
				<Name>Available</Name>
				<Operations>R</Operations>
				<MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
				<Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
				<Type>Boolean</Type>
				<RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
				<Units></Units>
				<Description><![CDATA[True if the Missions functionality is available in this product, false otherwise.]]></Description>
			</Item>
			<Item ID="2">
				<Name>CurrentMission</Name>
				<Operations>R</Operations>
				<MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
				<Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
				<Type>Unsigned Integer</Type>
				<RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
				<Units></Units>
				<Description><![CDATA[Currently selected mission.]]></Description>
			</Item>
			<Item ID="3">
				<Name>ClearProgress</Name>
				<Operations>E</Operations>
				<MultipleInstances>Single</MultipleInstances>
				<Mandatory>Mandatory</Mandatory>
				<Type></Type>
				<RangeEnumeration></RangeEnumeration>
				<Units></Units>
				<Description><![CDATA[Clears progress of a mission and will be set to 0% progress.

# Parameters
* 0: missionId: type: Unsigned Integer, units: ""
]]></Description>
			</Item>
		</Resources>
		<Description2><![CDATA[A mission in the mower is something that the mower can be asked to do. In general, a mission defines *what*, *where*, and *how* something shall be done. Note that it does not define when, this is handled by the Calendar, which points out missions from its tasks.

##### What
So far, our mowers can only mow grass, so this is always mow. There are not settings for this, that may be added when our products can do other things.

##### Where
The mission points out one of the working areas in the site map. That specifies where the mission shall be performed.

##### How
The mission family contains settings that specifies how a mission shall be performed. Settings that are common to all types of missions are available through the Missions family. A specific mission type can extend the number of settings, this is done in the specific mission families such as SystematicMissions.

## Common attributes for all mission types
All missions, regardless of mission type, have a number of common attributes.

- Unique id
- Mission type
- Name
- Cutting height
- Mowing area name. This name refers to one of the polygons in the map that is given to the SiteMap.

## Types of missions

##### Default mission
All "standard" mowers with traditional loop sensors have a default mission, with id 0. This mission is the same at is has always been, i.e. to mow the lawn within the boundaries of the loop wire.

##### Random mission
For mowers with hirep (good position), a random mission means that it shall mow the specified area using irregular pattern. This mission has few specific settings, but points out a working area to mow.

A mower that support the random missions type, contains the family RandomMissions and will respond True to RandomMissions.GetAvailable().

##### Systematic mission
For mower with hirep, a systematic mission means that it shall mow systematically. This mission type has a number of specific settings, such as:

- Default mowing direction
- Direction alternation
- Edge cutting enabled or disabled

A mower that support the systematic missions type, contains the family SystematicMissions and will respond True to SystematicMissions.GetAvailable(). The specific settings listed above are also available through the SystematicMissions family.

##### Focus area mission (zone control)
For mowers with lorep (normal loop system), this mission type can be used to roughly specify a part of the garden that shall be mowed. For instance, a working area can be defined to cover the front yard but not the back yard. When the mower runs this mission, it will consider the entire garden as a transport area, and the specified area as the working area.

A mower that support the focus area missions type, contains the family FocusAreaMissions and will respond True to FocusAreaMissions.GetAvailable().
]]></Description2>
	</Object>
</LWM2M>
